do you want to see what the world is
really like
yes I find the world a complicated Place
three we imagine a future two and our
imaginings horrifier us
why stop it there's going to be some
changes
made I love people so much it's hard for
me to be
alone I need you here people want to
love
you you should let him love all of
you humans only have one
ending ideas live forever imagine
knowing that you could do
something that only you could
do the world will remember this
day close your
eyes now feel
[Music]
[Applause]
you're so
beautiful I know I was just thinking
that I haven't eaten in 3
weeks I'm so hungry I have to go host
the Oscars
[Music]
live from the doie theater at OAS
Hollywood please welcome tonight's host
Jimmy
Kimel thank you thank you thank you hi
everybody well it's very kind thank
you thank you very much
thank you for that partial Standing
Ovation and welcome to the 96th Oscar
everybody look at these beautiful human
actors what an honor it is to be here
thank you for having me back and
congratulations to each and every one of
you for making it to the Academy Awards
and for making it on time the uh show as
you know is starting an hour early this
year but don't worry it will still end
very very late in fact
we're already 5 minutes over and I am
not
joking I'm not going to lie it's going
to be a long night after what was a long
year it was a hard year but it was also
a great year for movies despite the fact
that everything stopped the people in
this room somehow managed to come up
with so many excellent films and so many
memorable performances this night is
full of enormous talent and Untold
potential but so was Madame Webb so who
knows are we off to a bumpy start
okay this is a meaningful occasion for
most of you I know that and I know that
winning an Oscar is something you
dreamed about since you were a kid and
now here we are all dressed up
celebrating the best of the best
beginning with the biggest movie of the
year Barbie Barbie was a monster
hit what a thing what an achievement to
take a plastic doll nobody even liked
anymore I mean my wife before this movie
you'd have had a better of getting my
wife to buy our daughter a pack of maror
Reds than a Barbie doll now Barbie's a
feminist icon thanks to Greta gerwick
who many believe deserve to be nominated
for best
director hold
on I know you're clapping but you're the
ones who didn't vote for her by the way
don't act like you had nothing to do
with this and I don't want to leave out
Margo Robbie Margo put this giant hit
together
he he did Margot
Robbie and Ryan goling are here tonight
look kids it's Barbie and Ken sitting
just near each other Ryan and Margot I
want you to know that even if neither
one of you wins an Oscar tonight you
both already won the something much more
important the genetic
[Applause]
Lottery Ryan you are so
hot let's go camping together and not
tell our
wives and then we have the other major
box office winner this
year Oppenheimer directed by the great
Christopher Nolan also a very attractive
man and this is a very this a
fascinating person Christopher Nolan
doesn't have a smartphone he doesn't use
email he and he writes his scripts on a
computer with no internet connection
which is a powerful way of saying I will
not allow my porn addiction to get in
the way of my work
Christopher is joined by his longtime
collaborator Killian Murphy who is just
wonderful Killian
is interesting fact about his name it's
pronounced Killian when he does drama
when he does comedy it's
sanne and congratulations to selanne's
co-star Robert Downey Jr who is this
night
is but look at him I mean look at this
guy he's so handsome so talented he's
won every award there is to win is that
an acceptance speech in your pocket or
do you just have a very rectangular
penis what a story not even 20 years ago
things weren't going that great for
Robert he played the villain and correct
me if I have this wrong in a movie where
Tim Allen turns into a dog right and if
you ever decide to remake that film I
have just a guy to play Tim Allen that
is where is he
Messi
who even though he's a dog may have
given the performance of the year in
anatomy of a fall Messi has an overdose
scene if you've seen it you know it is
incredible honestly I haven't seen a
french actor eat vomit like that since
Gerard
deardo the second most nominated movie
of the year is poor things directed by
Euros Lanos
there he
is not only is Yos nominated for best
director his editor whose name is also
Yos yourh mavra serus is nominated too
we have two yoses in the house
tonight will they both win your ghost is
as good as
mine all right let's get uh 20 seconds
for room
tone Emma Stone is an Oscar nominee for
fifth time right the fifth time this is
and she is Emma you
are you're so unbelievably great in poor
things Emma played an adult woman with
the brain of a child like the lady who
gave the rebuttal to the State of the
Union on Thursday
night
and and you were just amazing there were
so many great movies that held audiences
captive this year and I mean that
literally your movies were too long this
year the average length of the top 10
movies was 2 hours and 23 minutes that's
up 30 minutes from 3 years ago when I
went to see killers of the flower Moon I
had my mail forwarded to the
theater killers of the flower moon is so
long in the time it takes you to watch
it you could drive to Oklahoma and solve
the murders
yourself the multi-talented Bradley
Bradley Cooper is here with us tonight
with his he's got another best picture
nominee
with Maestro Bradley you brought your
mom to the show tonight hi Mrs Cooper
how are you you're doing good great uh
Bradley brings his mother to every award
show right she was dated last year at
the Oscars and not okay but the and the
Tony and the uh Soul Train Awards Etc
it's very sweet but I guess the question
is how many times can one bring his mom
as his date before he is actually dating
his
mom are you working on a movie about
Freud right now and not telling us
here's some fun Oscar trivia 48 years
ago Robert dairo and jod Foster were
nominated for taxi driver and they are
both nominated again
tonight 1976 was the
year and that's pretty
crazy in 1976 jod Foster is young enough
to be Robert Dinero's daughter now she's
20 years too old to to be his
girlfriend I also want to congratulate
Robert's co-star Lily Gladstone who is
the first Native American ever to be
nominated for best
actress and she um for killers of the
flower Moon and if you saw it you know
that it was rivetting and did you know
that before she got this movie Lily was
ready to quit acting and take a job at
the Department of Agriculture tracking
murder Hornets right yeah and now she's
nominated for an Oscar which is so great
for her but also makes me worried that
no one's tracking these murder
Hornets Lily is an excellent company we
have many first-time acting nominees
tonight including Emily Blunt Jeffrey
Wright Sterling K Brown America
Ferrera America Danielle Brooks Coleman
Domingo Davon Joy Randolph and Sandra
huler for the first time three foreign
language films are up for best picture
and two of them star Sandra hooler which
is I
mean
Sandra two movies Sandra plays a woman
on trial for murdering her husband in
anatomy of a fall and a Nazi housewife
Living Next to aitz in the zone of
interest and while these are very heavy
subjects for American movie goerss in uh
Sandra's native Germany they're called
romcoms
for the first time in more than two
decades we're adding a new category to
the Oscars not tonight don't worry in
the future they will be adding an Oscar
for achievement in casting which yeah
you better you better applaud for
that and that is great news for actors
because now not only we'll be able to
watch someone else win an Oscar for a
part you didn't get you will also be
able to watch the person who didn't
think you were right for it win one
to what a year we've had it was a tough
year remember that kid from the
faban this is what he looks like
now very good to have you here
Stephen Stephen are you nominated
tonight or are you here because you have
season
tickets Stephen and his wife Kate Capa
donated a lot of money to help actors
and riters who were out of work over the
summer we were on strike for a long time
for 148 days
for five months this group of writers
actors directors the people who actually
make the film said we will not accept a
deal well not the directors you guys
folded immediately but the rest of
us said we will not accept a deal
without protections against artificial
intelligence and as a result actors no
longer have to worry about getting
replaced by AI thanks to this historic
agreement actors are now able to go back
to worrying about being replaced by
younger more attractive Ive people and I
think that's great and writers could AI
have written Transformers rise of the
beasts yes the answer is yes we learned
a lot while we're out on those picket
lines this the strike raised existential
questions about our industry like if a
movie premieres at the Grove and there
are no actors there to promote it does
Mario Lopez make a
sound and now that the strike is over
now that Fran dresser has returned to
her volunteer work reading loudly to the
hearing impaired we can be proud of the
fact that this long and difficult work
stoppage taught us that this very
strange town of ours as pretentious and
superficial as it can be at its heart is
a union town it's it's not just a bunch
of heavily botoxed haly Bieber smoothie
drinking diabetes prescription abusing
Gluten Sensitive nepo babies with
perpetually shivering Chihuahuas this is
a coalition of strong hardworking
mentally tough American laborers with
women and men who would 100% for sure
die if we even had to touch the handle
of a
shovel but the reason we were able to
make a deals because of the people who
rallied beside us so before we celebrate
ourselves let's have a very
well-deserved Round of Applause for the
people who work behind the scenes the
teamsters the truck drivers the lighting
crew sound camera gappers
grips that's right all the people who
refuse to cross the picking lines there
they are
if you're wearing sketches to the Oscars
Take a Bow come on guys take a bow Take
a Bow you deserve a thank you for
standing with
us and also we want you to know
that in your upcoming negotiation we
will stand with you
too and also I'm going to make sure this
show goes really long tonight so you get
a ton of overtime
it's golden time everybody should we
give out some Oscars all right we have
surprises planned for each of the acting
categories tonight five surprises in
fact and we're going to kick it off with
the Oscar for actress in a supporting
[Music]
role the Oscar goes to Mary Steen Bon
litao
Jamie Marino Regina King
[Music]
[Applause]
so I am thrilled to be back on this
stage to present this year's Best
Supporting Act Actress Oscar and I am
beyond proud to be able to talk about
one of my
besties so in niad jod Foster brings a
physical intensity coupled with deep
concern and care as Bonnie stole to
Diana nyad's Fierce best friend
motivator and serious ass kicker and
speaking from personal experience all of
those qualities are very real about jod
as well there is no one you would rather
have your back than the multi-talented
jod
[Applause]
Foster in the last moments of
Oppenheimer Emily blend's character
Kitty bising Oppenheimer refuses to
shake the offered hand of the man who
betrayed her husband hband though it was
years later her eyes had lost none of
their Fury if you saw only that
extraordinary moment you would know why
Emily Blunt is nominated
tonight Emily I am so proud to be your
friend and I am shaking my head in
Wonder the beautiful heartbreaking and
hellbent depths that you Brave to play
kitty Oppenheimer
when we meet Mary in the cafeteria in
the holdovers we can feel the unspoken
grief simmering under her surface dine
my friend your performance is tribute to
those who have helped others heal in
spite of their own pain it's also
tribute to your grandmother whose
glasses you wore in the film
what an honor to see the world through
her eyes and
yours
[Music]
America
America her powerful Barbie monologue is
perhaps the most talked about moment in
the most talked about movie of the past
year your
words and the passion with which you
delivered them about the most impossible
standards females must try to live up to
galvanized not only women but everyone
with a pulse
America from one woman to another
congratulations on your tour to
force Danielle
Brooks when you were 15 and saw the
color purple on Broadway with your
father a spark ignited in you and that
spark brought you here
today from making your Broadway debut 10
years later as Sophia to almost 10 years
after that giving this Transcendent
performance on the big screen we don't
just see Sophia's
strength but we see her vulnerability as
well you you have earned this full
circle moment my friend
[Applause]
and the Oscar goes to
[Music]
Devine this is the first Oscar win and
nomination for dine Joy
[Music]
God is so
good God is so good you
know I
um I didn't think I was supposed to be
doing this as a career I started off as
a
singer and my mother said to me go
across that street to that theater
Department there's something for you
there and I thank my mother for doing
that I thank you to all the people who
have stepped in my path and has been
there for me me who has ushered me and
guided me I am so grateful to all you
beautiful people out here all the women
who have been by my side Colleen km
Barbara Brockley Tracy Brenan Sarah
Fargo I have to give a special shout out
to my publicist and I know y'all said
don't say nothing about no publicist but
you don't have a publicist like I have a
publicist you have been by my side
through the entire thing and I am
forever grateful I pray pray to God that
I get to do this more than once I thank
you for seeing me have a blessed night
thank you so
[Applause]
much by the way congratulations to Davon
Joy Randol that was uh got your Oscar
very sweet beautiful speech you know you
forgot to mention your publicist's name
I think your your publicist needs a
publicist is what it it
is
yeah okay okay you shouldn't have to pay
for the rest of the year at
least great story about dine dine had to
learn how to smoke for her role in the
holdovers her director Alexander Payne
mailed her boxes of fake cigarettes so
she could practice but she didn't think
the fake ones look right right so she
started smoking real cigarettes and now
she has an Oscar you see kids sometimes
smoking is fine
and by the way I do want to say um for
those of you who do not win an Oscar I
need you to stick around after the show
uh we'll be giving out the silver Oscars
for second place after an allnew Abbot
Elementary so please stay our next
awards are for animated feature and
animated short raise your hand if you
let your kid fill out this part of the
ballot okay good it is not allowed
please welcome the god of thunder and
Princess Peach Chris Hemsworth and Anna
Taylor
[Applause]
Joy the great artist can come from
[Music]
anywhere that's all it is a leap of
faith
here are the nominees for best animated
feature the boy in the Heron ha Miyazaki
and toshio
Suzuki Elemental p and Denise
re nimono Nick Bruno Troy quain Karen
Ryan and Julie
Zachary robot dreams Pablo be
ion ignas stape and Sandra Tapia Diaz
Spider-Man across the spiderverse Kemp
Powers Justin K Thompson Phil Lord
Christopher Miller and Amy
Pascal all right and the Oscar goes to
the boy and the
Heron the boy and the herens haki and
Tosh Suzuki cannot be here with us
tonight so we accept this Oscar on their
behalf congratulations
[Applause]
[Music]
really the boy and the Heron people
couldn't make it I mean I could see
maybe the boy not showing up but the
Heron should be
here our next Oscars are for best
original and adapted screenplay which is
actually a controversial category this
year CU a lot of people want to know at
what age do you tell a screenplay it was
adapted
our next presenters have been best
friends for almost 30 years and that all
Ends Tonight please welcome two-time
Oscar nominee Melissa McCarthy and Oscar
winner Octavia
[Applause]
[Music]
Spencer original screenplays and adapted
screenplays are Cut From the Same Cloth
they're similar yet they remain unique
yet each art form maintains its
individual characteristics it's kind of
like us right I mean we do our own
things we also do our things together
we're like that chip Andale of show biz
right chip yeah yeah I don't see us as
the ly rep pant pelvic thrust types well
speak for yourself but uh what are you
talking I said chip Andale you said chip
Andale no I'm oh no I'm I'm saying chip
in Dale Chip in comma Dale and you're
saying Chip and Dale z Oh I thought you
were saying chi andales chi andales well
usually I am saying Chi andales but not
not now cuz it's that would be weird
yeah yeah yeah yeah why don't we uh just
read what the brilliant writers wrote
for us oh oh my god look look that
there's a there's a script on the thing
and it has my name up there look at it a
it's in yellow yes to make a script
really come to life the writer must not
only Capt the audience's hearts but
simultaneously entertain and
surprise wow that is better when it's
much better it's better written much
better it's better written guys much
better written here are the nominees for
best original
screenplay anatomy of a fall screenplay
By Justine Trier and Artur orari you're
not a victim not at all your generosity
concealed something dirtier and
meaner the holdovers written by David
hson I can't fail this class oh don't
sell yourself short Mr coats I truly
believe that you can Maestro written by
Bradley Cooper and Josh singland you I
slept with both your parents too much is
it too much I love too much what can I
say but I'm raining it in I'm raining it
in May December screenplay by Sammy bur
Story by Sammy bur and Alex mechanic
insecure people are very dangerous
aren't
they I'm secure past lives written by
[Applause]
Seline and the Oscar goes
to anatomy of a fall
arari this is the first Oscar win for
Justine Trier and Ur Harari Justine
Trier is also nominated for directing
anatomy of
[Applause]
[Music]
a thank you
W
okay thank you so much WoW uh it will
help me uh through my midlife crisis I
think uh this is a crazy year um anyway
this glamour tonight con contrast
slightly with with all it what it start
before
uh we were stuck in a house with two
kids it was a lockdown and we hook them
up to cartoons to have
peace and uh yeah there is no line I
think between work and
diapers and and and then Along Came two
other people a woman and a man The
Producers Mari lucheni and and David T
and uh yeah and they actually that's
when things got a little crazy it was
like um mix doubl pink pong play byic
French nerd something and uh but there
was nothing between us or above us only
uh total Independence and freedom and
that's the only way we could make that
film so uh that's for
that I I want to thank all the cast of
course Sandra Swan Milo all the cast for
what you did on on Set You Killed the
script on set and it that's what we we
that's the best for white for writers
for directors thank you so much thank
you it's such an honor thank
[Music]
you oh it's me it's you here are the
nominees for adapted
screenplay American fiction written for
the screen by for Jefferson based upon
the novel eraser by pel ever is seeing a
dead body ever become normal I don't
know I haven't seen many really I'm a
plastic surgeon if I'm looking at a
corpse and something went very AR right
the zone of Interest written by Jonathan
Glazer based on the novel by Martin
Amos that
[Music]
Oppenheimer written for the screen by
Christopher Nolan based on the book
American Prometheus the Triumph and
tragedy of J Robert Oppenheimer by Kai
bird and Martin J Sherwin algebra's like
sheet music the important thing isn't
can you read music it's can you hear it
can you hear the music
Rober yes I
can Barbie written by Greta GG and Noah
bom based on Barbie by metall I'm just
so tired of watching myself and every
single Other Woman tie herself into
knots so that people will like
us poor things screenplay by Tony mcir
based upon the novel by alist gray it is
your body Bella Baxter yours to give
freedom I generally charged 30 Franks
well that seems
low and the Oscar goes those to American
fiction this is the first Oscar win and
second nomination this year for Fore
Jefferson who is also nominated as part
of the producing team of American
fiction
[Music]
wow thank you so much thank you so
much my God uh look this is thank you so
much thank you so
much this really this means the world to
me thank you so much to the academy
um thank you so much to everybody who
worked on the film you I've been talking
a lot about how many people passed on
this movie and discussing it and I worry
that that sometimes sounds vindictive
and I don't want to be vindictive I'm
not a vindictive person anymore I've
worked very hard to not be vindictive
anymore and it's more a plea it's a plea
to acknowledge and recognize that there
are so many people out there who want
the opportunity that I was given and
this is a I understand that this there I
only got six seconds seconds please uh I
understand that this is a risk averse
industry I get it um but it $200 million
movies are also a risk you know and and
and it doesn't always work out but you
take the risk anyway and instead of
making one $200 million movie try making
20 $10 million movies or or 50
50 right 50 uh uh $4 million movies like
you can there are so many people I just
feel so much joy being here I I felt so
much joy making this movie and I want
other people to experience that joy and
they are out there I promise you the
next Martin Scorsese is out there the
next Greta Greta is out there both
gretas the next the next Christopher
Nolan's out there I promise you they
just want a shot and we can give them
one and this has changed my life thank
you all who worked on this movie for for
trusting a 40-year-old black guy who
never directed anything before it has
changed my life thank you so I love you
all thank you so much
[Music]
please welcome Dwayne Johnson and Bad
Bunny
[Applause]
beautifully said you see he's not such a
bad
bunny happy birthday brother graia thank
you International films enrich our
cultural understanding by broadening our
perspectives of the world and each other
here are the nominees for international
feature
film from Italy IO Capitano directed by
Matteo
gone from Japan perfect days directed by
Vim
vendors from Spain Society of the snow
directed by J
Bona from Germany the Teachers Lounge
directed by eare
chatak from the United Kingdom the zone
of Interest directed by Jonathan
Glazer and the
O and the Oscar goes
to the son of
Interest this is the third nomination
for the United Kingdom the zone of
interest is the ninth non-english
language film to be nominated for both
International feature film and best
picture in the same year
thank you so much I'm going to read I'm
afraid thank you to the academy for this
honor and to our partners a24 film for
Access and the Polish Film Institute to
the aitz burken our state museum for
their trust and guidance to my producers
actors collaborators all our choices
were made to reflect and confront Us in
the present not to say look what they
did then rather look what we do now our
film shows where DEH onization leads at
its worst it shaped all of our past and
present right now we stand here as men
who refute their jewishness and the
Holocaust being hijacked by an
occupation which has led to Conflict for
so many innocent people whether the
victims of
[Applause]
October whether the victims of October
the 7th in Israel or the ongoing attack
on Gaza all the victims of this
dehumanization how do we
resist Alexandra biston
kadich the girl who glows in the film as
she did in life chose to I dedicate this
to her memory and her resistance thank
you
[Music]
[Applause]
h
[Music]
[Applause]
to
[Music]
[Applause]
what
[Music]
[Applause]
wo
[Music]
you guys all right you're hanging in
everybody
okay apparently a lot of people watching
at home are just uh just turning it on
and they're upset because they thought
the show started at 5:00 like it usually
does so anyway the producers and I just
talked and we think the best thing to do
is uh to start the show over again so
let's take it from the top everybody
take it a one no we're not you know
we're like an hour and a half into the
show if this was an AMC theater the
movie would just be starting right
now our next category is for actor in a
supporting role and we have a whole
bunch of Oscar winners to support it
please welcome your best supporting
[Applause]
actors and the Oscar goes to Sam
Rockwell Tim
Robbins vs Maha Ali
[Applause]
[Music]
it is an honor for us to be here to pay
tribute to the nominees for actor in a
supporting
role Sterling
I know yours has been a long journey to
get to this
night I can relate and I'm so so happy
that you're finally being recognized by
your peers uh your performance in
American fiction is extraordinary and
transformative and I am in a
the magic you bring on screen it's
outmatched only that by the magic of who
you are as a
person there are
actors and then there are actors who
don't drop character until the DVD
commentary talking about Robert Downey
Jr that dude
Susan's husband could be Iron Man he
could be every man he always goes above
and beyond 30 years ago and as chaplain
he learned how to play the violin
left-handed who does that seriously it's
obnoxious and now an Oppenheimer he
steals scenes from Albert Einstein and
the atomic bomb I love him you love him
we couldn't be happier for his third
Oscar nom for his amazing portrayal as
Strauss in the course of His Brilliant
career Robert dairo has
te has teamed with Martin scorsi to
bring us a wide range of uniquely
complicated villains his latest
performance in killers of the flower
Moon delivers a different type of evil
not of a mobster or psychotic loner but
of a businessman consumed by greed and
his lust for power Mr dairo in an Oscar
winning Oscar worthy performance gives
us should be
winning gives us a reminder of the Heart
of Darkness within our ancestral blood
congratulations to an acting Legend
it's not really new that certain male
Behavior looks like the inferiority
complex of a plastic doll in a cardboard
box but it's something easy to ridicule
so why then do we admire Ryan Gosling's
Ken so
much because Ryan's portrayal of Ken
allows us to yeah I admit it to
connect not not because it's ridiculous
but because it is funny intelligent
hugely entertaining and ultimately
poignant and deserving of empathy to
experience all that is exactly what we
go to the movies
for Mark Ruffalo
over three decades you've captivated us
with your
versatility from drama to Comedy to
action you've defied
categorization and we wouldn't have it
any other
way your appetite for challenges is
unmatched exemplified by your portrayal
of Duncan weird in poor things which has
rightfully earned you this nomination
ation and beyond your talent mark You're
simply a wonderful human being thank
[Applause]
you and the Oscar goes
to Robert Downey Jr
this is the first Oscar win for Robert
Downey Jr and his third
[Music]
nomination thank you thank
you uh thanks Sam thanks fellas that's
amazing you only one
line I'd like to thank my terrible
childhood and the
academy in that
order I'd like to thank my I
veterinarian I meant wife uh Susan
Downey over
there she found me a snarling rescue pet
and you love me back to life that's why
I'm here thank
you
um here's my little secret I needed this
job more than it needed me Chris knew it
Emma made sure that she R surrounded me
with one of the great casts and Crews of
all time Emily Killian Matt Damon blunt
it was fantastic and I I stand here
before you a better man because of it
you know what we do is Meaningful and
the stuff that we decide to make is
important um so back to my publicist uh
my agent Philip Raskin is here and
Andrew Dunlap my uh DM mother uh Joy
fely thank you very much I'm want to
thank my stylist in case no one else
does thanks Erica thank you very much um
and I'm just gonna uh say this um my
entertainment lawyer Tom Hansen of 40
years the half of which he spent trying
to get me insured and bailing me out of
the husa
thanks bro um Avery xon India this one's
for you
[Applause]
[Music]
it doesn't seem to matter what I
do always number
two no one knows how hard I
try oh
I have
feelings I can't
explain driving me
insane all my life been so
polite I'll sleep alone
tonight I'm just K anywhere else I be
aain is it my destiny to live and die a
life of blun
fragility I'm just where I see love she
sees a friend what will it take for her
to see The Man Behind the T and fight
for
[Music]
me I want to know to to be the real
thing is cry might not when I'm in my
feeling it's my moment finally here
Am I
Dreaming I'm no
[Applause]
[Music]
dreamer sogy
I'm just
anywhere is
[Music]
my I'm just where I see love she
sees what will it take for her to see
The Man Behind the T he fight for me I'm
[Music]
just so hey Che me out yeah I'm just
kid
that in so hey well check me out I'm
just k
[Music]
[Applause]
no k
[Music]
[Applause]
look what I got off Ryan Gosling's
body we'll start the bidding at
$10,000 oh Bradley Cooper's mother yes
you
say no this is going home with me sorry
ladies here to present the Oscars for
outstanding original score and song
Please welcome Ariana Grande and
two-time Oscar nominee Cynthia arivo
[Music]
[Applause]
we're here to present the Oscar for
original song and original School score
a great movie song can set the mood
reveal something about a character and
help us tell a story and a great film
score can even leave a handprint on our
hearts forever it can ignite wonder and
astonishment make us feel sadness and
longing and can even transport us to new
worlds or somewhere over the rainbow
where the dreams that you dare to dream
really do come true oh how wickedly
subtle of you I do
try and now here are the nominees for
original School
American fiction by Laura
[Music]
[Applause]
Cartman Indiana Jones and the dial of
Destiny by John
Williams killers of the flower Moon by
Robbie
Robertson Oppenheimer by Ludi Genson
[Applause]
poor things by Justin
[Music]
fendrick and the Oscar goes
to
Oppenheimer this is the second Oscar win
and third nomination for ludig Goron who
took home his first Oscar in this
category for black
[Applause]
Panther wow um thank you um Christopher
noan and Matas for inviting me on this
incredible world uh Christopher Nolan it
was your idea to use a violin in the
score and it allowed me to work and
collaborate with my wonderful wife and a
claimed violin is Serena Goron um
we we had uh we recording at night and
we were rushing to go home and put our
kids Apollo and Romeo down to bed uh but
the result of that was amazing and out
it really set a really nice tone for the
film of that performance um Tera
stanislav Jake Brown Chris Fogle Anthony
parur Alyssa Park thank you for making
the music sound great and to my parents
up there thank you for giving me guitars
and drum machines instead of video games
thank you
[Applause]
[Music]
all night you've seen performances of
this year's nominated songs and now it's
time for the award and the Oscar goes
to Billy iish
andine this is a second Oscar win and
second nomination for Billy ish and
Phineas okell the siblings took home
their first Oscar for the song no time
to die
[Applause]
[Music]
I had a nightmare about this last night
um um thank you so much to the academy I
feel like I I I don't I I just didn't
think this would happen I was not
expecting this I um I feel so incredibly
lucky and honored um thank you to Greta
where did you go I love you thank you
for
this I'm so grateful for this song and
for this movie and the way that it made
me feel and um this goes out to everyone
who was affected by the movie and how
incredible it is and I want to thank my
team and my parents I love you guys so
much thank you Paul Walker thank you
enan crat thank you Mark and Andrew for
making the song with us thank you um to
um Everybody yes Margot of course lucky
chap Tom um thank you to our parents
forever and ever and ever um thank you
to my best friends David and rat for
listening to all my music thank you
[Applause]
to we've only got four Awards left which
shouldn't take long and yet it
will but first it's time to find out who
will be named best actor and what a
lineup we've assembled to present here
with the Oscar for best actor please
welcome all five original members of
[Applause]
insync and the osar goes to Nicholas
Cage Matthew MCC Brendan faser Ben
Kingsley horis Whitaker
[Applause]
[Music]
we're here to speak about the great
talent of this year's five nominees for
actor in a leading
role when you see Jeffrey Wright in a
film you instantly know it's going to be
good because he's so
good Jeffrey in American fiction you are
funny and Furious and flawed and
empathetic and for the way that you
elevate the craft we're indebted to
you the greates go above and beyond in
their commitment to a role just as
Daniel D Lewis stating character as
Lincoln this past year Paul GM miti was
so committed that for the character to
have a lazy eye he wore a soft contact
lens during the entire shoot which made
him blind in that eye while
filming would I have done that hell yes
but the point is you did do it Paul and
you were brilliant again
bra a modernday renaissance
man nothing better describes
you sir Mr Bradley
Cooper who wrote directed produced and
acted in his latest film Maestro from
the script to the screen Bradley takes a
transformative journey into becoming
lonard Bernstein bringing to life all
the character Charisma and complex
Brilliance of an American icon
congratulations
[Applause]
Killian
Murphy he accepted the leading role of
Oppenheimer before even reading the
script which must have taken much
courage and trust or simple
Hotpot either way the performance is
masterful and endowing his portrayal
with layers of
humanity whilst his character created
something
inhuman it's riveting to
watch my
congratulations Coleman when I first
work with
you a decade
ago I saw that you were bold
brilliant Bound for greatness it's been
exciting to watch you light up the
screen over the years most recently with
your truly inspired portrayal of civil
rights leader Bard
Rustin Coleman your Genius is an actor
illuminates The Genius of an Angelic
Troublemaker who's nearly buried in the
history
books thankfully Justin is getting his
due as are you K Domingo
and the Oscar goes
to kilan
Murphy this is a first Oscar win and
nomination for Killian Murphy
[Applause]
[Music]
go
uh um I'm a little overwhelmed um thank
you to the
academy um Chris Nolan and Emma Thomas
it's been the the wildest most
exhilarating most creatively satisfying
Journey you've taken me on over the last
20 years I owe you more than I can say
thank you so much every single crew
member every single cast member on
Oppenheimer you guys carried me through
uh all my fellow nominees I remain in
awe of you guys truly I want to thank my
incredible team uh big shout out to
Craig bankey Brendan Murphy Brendan
Murphy Mary Murphy Ivon mcginness my
part learn life and art my two boys
malaky and Aaron who are sitting up
there I love you so much and I'm a very
proud Irish man standing here tonight
so you know we made a film we made a
film about the man who created the
atomic bomb and For Better or For Worse
we're all living in oppenheimer's world
so I would really like to dedicate this
to the peacemakers
[Applause]
[Music]
everywhere on the 30th Anniversary for
its win for best picture please welcome
the academy award-winning director of
Schindler's List Steven Spielberg
[Music]
[Applause]
at their very best films can do more
than entertain us they can open our
hearts to each other they can show us
ourselves and they can shine a light on
where we've been and make us think about
where we are going we are so fortunate
that this has been a great and eclectic
year for movies and a tri to all the
places these five nominated directors
have taken the entire
world jtine Trier anatomy of a
fall Martin scusi killers of the flower
Moon Christopher Nolan
Oppenheimer yorgos Lanos poor
things Jonathan Glazer the zone of
Interest
and the Oscar goes
to Christopher Nolan
Oppenheimer this is a first Oscar win
and eighth nomination for Christopher
Nolan he received his first nomination
for his momento screenplay
[Applause]
[Music]
thank
you uh there there are so many people
who who've dragged me up here um
Universal Studios Donna Langley thank
you for seeing the potential in this um
Kai bird and mared show and thank you
for the 25 years you put into the book
that this film is based on um I I have
have so many people to thank the most
incredible cast Matt Damon Robert Emily
Florence and so many others all at the
top of their game led by the incredible
Killian Murphy um and a crew some of
whom have been rewarded tonight I I
can't
say enough about the incredible crew
that we got together on this film um
thank you to Chuck Roven for putting the
book in my hands and um thank you for
those who been there for me and believed
in me my whole career uh Dan Michael my
brother Jonah my family um and the
incredible Emma Thomas
producer producer of of all our films
and all our children I love
you uh and and uh to the academy uh just
to say uh movies are just a little bit
over 100 years old I mean imagine being
there 100 years into painting or theater
we don't know where this incredible
journey is going from here but to know
that you think that I'm a meaningful
part of it means the world to me thank
you very
[Applause]
[Music]
much and the Oscar goes to charie field
Jennifer laen Michelle yo Char Jessica l
[Music]
[Applause]
it's an honor for us to present the
award for actress in leading roles the
amazing Sandra hoola is nominated for
her role in anatomy of a
fall as a woman accused of killing her
husband at the heart of this powerful
performance is how
maintains a certain ambiguity throughout
as if her character is capable of
committing that crime and here we are
Oscar Knight and I still don't know if
she did
it curious as a puppy and hungry as a
bear Emma Stone's brilliant belly is
unhinged uninhibited and completely
original with the fearlessness of a
toddler she awkwardly steps into the
world Awakening into her body and the
sensations of being alive without
boundaries it is an unforgettable and
endearing character created by an actor
who is always surprising who refuses to
be categorized and like Bella is
completely original Bravo and
Lily you are the soul of killers of the
flower
Moon every second of your performance as
Molly Burkhart is imbued with the plight
resilience and spirit of the oage people
your advocacy offset is a powerful
display of dedication and Leadership
Illuminating and helping us reconcile
one of the darkest parts of our
country's
history
congratulations
Annette I've never been stung by a
jellyfish but seeing you endure it
multiple times made me feel like I had
watching you portray Diane Diane nyed is
an intense sensory experience you can
taste the salt water feel the Sunburn
and relate to the Relentless
determination your work is a beautiful
illustration of how to navigate the
waves in the ocean and in life
[Applause]
in
Myro Carrie Mulligan radiates as Leonard
Bernstein's wife
Felicia shining a piercing light on
their complicated yet enduring love but
this level of Excellence is the norm for
carry for in every role she takes on she
infuses it with a unique Humanity
without this spectacular performance
Maestro would not have been the movie it
became Carrie you are so deserving of
this
honor and the Oscar goes
to Emma Stone
this is a second Oscar and fifth
nomination for Emma Stone she took home
her first Oscar for her leading
performance in la la land she is a
second woman to be nominated for acting
and best picture for the S CL
[Applause]
oh boy um my dress is
broken I think it happened during I'm
just
Ken I'm pretty
sure oh boy this is really this is
really overwhelming sorry i h okay my
voice is also a little gone whatever
um uh the women on the stage you are all
incredible in the women in this
category um Sandra Annette Carrie Lily I
share this with you I'm an awe of you
and it has been such an honor to do all
this together I hope we get to keep
doing more
together um I don't know what I'm saying
oh my God God I'm totally
okay the other night I was panicking as
you can kind of see happens a lot um
that maybe something like this could
happen and and yorgos said to me please
take yourself out of it and he was right
because it's not about me it's about a
team that came together to make
something greater than the sum of its
parts and that is the best part about
making
movies is all of us together and I am so
deeply honored to share this with every
cast member with every crew member with
every single person who poured their
love and their care and their Brilliance
into the making of This film in yorgo
thank you for the gift of a lifetime in
Bella Baxter I am forever thankful for
you thank you for inviting all of us to
be members of this team thank
you and I just oh wait I just
I know I have to wrap up but I really
just want to thank my family my mom my
brother Spencer my dad my husband Dave I
love you so much and most importantly my
daughter who's going to be three in
three days and has turned our lives
Technicolor I love you bigger than the
whole Sky my girl so thank you so much
don't look at the back of my dress thank
you
[Music]
[Applause]
guys make sure we tear up that envelope
so there's no confusion with the best
picture hi
everyone I was just uh you know this
this doing this show is not about me and
I I appr appreciate you having me is
really about you and uh Emma and all
these great actors and actresses and
filmmakers but U I was told we have like
an extra minute and um I'm really proud
of something uh I was wondering if I
could share it with you I just got a a
review and
um has there ever been a worse host than
Jimmy Kimmel at the
Oscars his opening was that of a less
than average person trying too hard to
be something which he is not and never
can be
get rid of Kimmel and perhaps replace
him with another washed up but cheap ABC
Talent George
slopis he would make everybody on stage
look bigger stronger and more glamorous
blah blah blah make America great
[Applause]
again okay now see if you can guess
which former president just posted that
on
TR anyone
no well thank you president Trump um
thank you for watching I'm surprised
you're still Isn't it past your jail
time let focused on the important stuff
for sure before we give out the final
award did anyone uh not get a chance to
give a speech we do have some time if
you have anything you want to say just
line up right here and we'll make sure
everybody gets a chance to talk now to
present our final Award of the evening
and to commemorate the 50th anniversary
of The Godfather Part Two a man who
created some of the most iconic
characters in movie history he's an
Oscar winner and a nine-time nominee and
we are so glad he was able to find a
sitter so he could be here tonight with
the award for best picture please
welcome Al Pino
[Applause]
[Music]
oh my
friends thank you thank you I don't know
did I do some Shakespeare now I think uh
is in order right uh to
be no I'm not going to do it oh no no no
sorry world this is the time uh for the
last award of the evening and it's uh uh
my honor to present it uh 10 wonderful
films uh were
nominated what
Happ wow
Oppenheimer has 13 nominations and has
won seven Oscars tonight for actor in a
supporting role film editing
cinematography original score actor in a
leading role directing and best picture
[Music]
[Applause]
wow oh my
goodness wow
um I think any of us who make movies
know that you kind of dream of this
moment you know you do right I could
deny it but I have been dreaming about
this moment for so long um but it seemed
so unlikely that it would ever actually
happen and now I'm standing here and
everything's kind of gone out of my head
um the the reason this movie was the
movie that it was was Chris Nolan um he
is
singular he is brilliant and um I'm so
grateful to you um
but as Emma said this is the thing
that's fantastic about our jobs is that
it's about collaboration it's about
teamwork and our team was just
incredible on this movie so thank you to
all of them both cast and crew thank you
to Universal um for supporting us um and
I want to
thank Rich gelfond at IMX um and
everybody else at IMX um for believing
in this movie when that maybe didn't
make that much sense to do so um thank
you to all the theaters um as a movie
goer and as a filmmaker it that's why
why we do what we do so thank you so
much and to my children Flora Rory
Oliver and Magnus who's not here tonight
thank you and it's UK Mother's Day so
I'm thinking of my mom who's no longer
with us today and my motherin-law
Christina who's here with my dad so
thank you oh and thank you to the
academy I'm so honored to to
be
here um I certainly want to thank the
academy I want to thank uh Universal
Pictures Donna Langley and the whole
team
there I of course um want to thank my my
family and uh my wife uh who always has
my back
and is uh as all my friends know the
secret weapon of my life and I also want
to thank James Woods and David Wargo for
trusting me to move this project forward
they gave me the book which I was
fortunate enough to give to Chris and
Emma and finally just want to say that
I've had this amazing 20 plus year
experience with Chris an Emma five
movies over 20 years and it's been one
of the most uh exhilarating experiences
I've ever had they're a fantastic team
and just to be part of making movies
with them has been completely thrilling
so thank you so much
oh isn't that great congratulations to
uh oppen har if only there was some way
for Christopher Nolan to text his family
to tell him the good
news that's it for our show I want to
thank the academy for having me I want
to thank our very hardworking producers
Raj kapor Katen Milan and Molly mcy
thanks to our great announcer David
Allen G Greer our band leader Ricky
Miner our band our director HH Hamilton
and the whole Oscars crew stay up for a
new avot elementary and join me on my
show tomorrow with Dwayne Johnson Justin
Timberlake and Robert DeNiro thanks for
watching the 96th Oscars good
night during the show Oscars were also
presented for animated short film War is
Over inspired by the music of John and
Yoko for makeup and hair styling for
things for production design poor things
for costume design poor things for
visual effects Godzilla minus
one for film editing
oppenheim for documentary short film The
Last repair
shop for documentary feature 20 days in
Maro for cinematography
Oppenheimer for liveaction short film
The Wonderful story of Henry sugar for
sound the zone of Interest
[Music]
la